<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Tom Preston-Werner</title>
 <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/"/>
 <updated>2012-10-24T11:25:26-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Tom Preston-Werner</name>
   <email>tom@mojombo.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>PHP needs a better bridge</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/2012/10/23/php-needs-a-bridge.html"/>
   <updated>2012-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/2012/10/23/php-needs-a-bridge</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I learned PHP because I needed to coerce WordPress 2.5 into being a CMS for a client's website. I was pretty new to the full-stack freelancer gig, and by &quot;pretty new&quot; I mean completely and totally unqualified with absolutely no experience with anything but HTML and CSS and maybe a little JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the PHP community has a bad reputation because of people like me who were able to so easily fake it as a &quot;programmer&quot; (I never used that word to describe myself until very recently) by throwing together a few functional PHP scripts. You have to know something about the command line and about servers and about &lt;em&gt;programming&lt;/em&gt; to get a simple Ruby or Python or Java project up and running. With PHP, you can install MAMP and get a script running in a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That kind of learning curve is usually described as a strength of PHP, but it encourages a culture of sloppy, irresponsible code. It's possible to do &quot;real&quot; programming in PHP and I've been learning a ton about just that over the last 2 years. But the path from WordPress hacker to programmer wasn't clear to me at all. We don't have a bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why do you hate WordPress?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like WordPress a lot, actually. And if all you need to do is get a Loop running, maybe you don't need to worry about anything else, but I think a lot of WordPress developers could become better at WordPress (or Drupal, or whatever) by learning about programming in general. This isn't about &quot;Fuck WordPress use a real framework&quot;, this is about becoming a better community of code writers together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's why we need a bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>